<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Android | Aaron Liew's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://aaronliew.github.io/blog/categories/android/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aaronliew.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-11T18:27:16+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://aaronliew.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aaron Liew]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie Searching App- Coding Explanation]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronliew.github.io/blog/2014/03/11/day-six/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-11T09:10:50+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronliew.github.io/blog/2014/03/11/day-six</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are five packages in this app as shown in the figure below.
<img class="center" src="/images/DaySix/PackageChart.JPG" title="Package Chart" >
In each of these packages, it contains classes as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>MovieSearchingApp package

<ul>
<li>MainActivity.Java</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>IO package

<ul>
<li>FlushedInputStream.Java</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Model package

<ul>
<li>Movies.Java</li>
<li>MoviesResult.Java</li>
<li>Person.Java</li>
<li>PersonResult.Java</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Services package

<ul>
<li>GenericSeeker.Java</li>
<li>MovieSeeker.Java</li>
<li>PersonSeeker.Java</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<p>In order to explain the purpose of class and package and also show the interaction
between the package and classes, the chart was constructed as shown in the figure below.
<img class="center" src="/images/DaySix/CodingExplanation.png" title="Coding Explanation" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie Searching App- Online Searching Function]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronliew.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/day-five/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T21:02:24+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronliew.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/day-five</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Basically, there are two types of search in this app: Movie and Person.
<img class="center" src="/images/DayFive/Classification.JPG" title="Classification" ></p>

<p>The flowchart on how movie searching app works is shown in the figure below.
<img class="center" src="/images/DayFive/FlowChart.JPG" title="FlowChart" ></p>

<p>There are two additional features that I have added in the android applications:
Progress Bar and Online Searching function. The Progress Bar is the indication of
the progress of retrieving the JSON data from the URL. The online searching function
includes retrieve the data from the URL and convert the JSON format to JAVA Object
using GSON library. There were problems I have encountered in the process of
completing the task as shown below.</p>

<p>1)Problem: API of movie database was upgraded to version 3, therefore, all the data is presented in
JSON format instead of XML format</p>

<p><em>Solution: Use the GSON libray to convert JSON format into Data Object and display relevant data in the form
of pop-up message at the bottom of the app.</em></p>

<p>2)Problem: Method to acquire the data from the movie database</p>

<p><em>Solution:  Acquire API key of the movie database. Construct the URL with API key in order to obtain JSON data.</em></p>

<p>3)Problem: NetworkOnMainThread Exception occur while retrieving data from database</p>

<p><em>Solution: Async task was used to solve the &ldquo;NetworkOnMainThread&rdquo; exception error.</em></p>

<p>The operation of app is explained and the result of the movie searching app is shown as follows:</p>

<p>First of all, with movie-search type, the text &ldquo;inception&rdquo; was entered as shown in the figure below.
The progress bar is shown while obtaining the data from the url after user clicks on the &ldquo;Search Button&rdquo;.
<img class="center" src="/images/DayFive/MovieSearch.png" title="FlowChart" ></p>

<p>After data is obtained, the movie title and popularity are shown in the pop-up message.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/DayFive/MovieResult.png" title="FlowChart" ></p>

<p>For person-search type, the operation is same as the movie-search type as shown in the figures below.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/DayFive/PersonSearch.png" title="FlowChart" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/DayFive/PersonResult.png" title="FlowChart" ></p>

<p>In the next blog, I will discuss about detail description of structure of coding and ways to troubleshoot
the bug of the app.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android App: Interaction Between Two Activities]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaronliew.github.io/blog/2014/02/25/day-two/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T09:37:09+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaronliew.github.io/blog/2014/02/25/day-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First of all, user will insert text into the textbox and press the &lsquo;send&rsquo; button.
In MainActivity class, the &lsquo;intent&rsquo; object store the values. Next, the DisplayMessageActivity
will display the message which is inserted by the user. In order to have clearer picture on the
operation of Android app and interactions between classes, I have created the charts as shown below.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/DayTwo/ExplanationOfActivities.JPG" title="Explanation Of Activities" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/DayTwo/ClassInteraction.JPG" title="Interaction between class" ></p>

<p>The result is shown in figure below.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/DayTwo/Screenshot.JPG" title="Screenshot" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
